David Darden

Software Developer

davidedarden83@gmail.com
931-247-5622
LinkedIn/david-darden
github/DavidEdwardDarden
PersonalSite/davidedwarddarden

About

Teacher/ Veteran turned Web Dev Professional. Life-long learner. Always striving to be Humble, Hungry, and Smart. I am focused on software development and working with database systems. I have a broad range of professional experiences that give me a unique perspective when solving and analyzing problems. I work well in a team and can adapt to new challenges.

I am currently attending Nashville Software School's Web Development Bootcamp. I am developing my programming skills and feel that I can learn new processes quickly. I find that success comes through relationships that encourage collaboration, communication, and results.

Technical Skills

- C#
- ASP.Net
- React
- SQL
- Access
- JavaScript
- Adobe Illustrator
- Excel
- Web Design

- Business App Design
- Microsoft Visual Studio
- Visual Studio Code
- Entity Relationship Diagrams
- LucidChart
- DBDiagram

- GitHub
- Slack
- Database Systems and Design
- Business Processes
- CSS/HTML
- XMind
- Brackets
- Python

Technical Experience

Nashville Software School, Software Developer

February 2021- August 2021

Full-time, six month, software development bootcamp. The first three months covers front end web development (JS, React, CSS, HTML). The final 3 months covers back end web development (C#, .NET, SQL) and concludes with a capstone project.

- Front End Capstone Project- "New Image Nation" allows users to upload and share Composite Images and their individual elements within a community. Developed using Visual Studio Code. Created ERD with DBDiagram. Created a custom dataset in a JSON file. Created wireframe with Miro. Uploaded images using Cloudinary. (JS, React, CSS, HTML)
- Back End Capstone Project (Firebase, C#, JS, React, HTML, CSS)
- JS, React, CSS, HTML, Firebase, C#

Professional Experience

Middle School / High School Art Teacher, McCreary County Schools

August 2016- May 2018, Stearns KY

- Establish and maintain open communication by conducting conferences with parents, students, principals, and teachers
- Oversee process of maintaining and storing all art supplies
- Present subject matter according to guidelines, board policies, and administrative regulations

Substitute Teacher, Russellville Independent Schools and Logan County Schools August 2015 -May 2016, Russellville KY

- Present organized learning materials for students in accordance with approved curriculum
- Encourage development of students in thoughtful, caring and professional manner

Soldier, United States Army, 1st Battalion 160th Special Operations Aviation Regiment (Airborne)

Jan 2009- Nov 2015 160th SOAR(A), Oak Grove KY

- Led the setup of deployment of Refueling Point Packages for both Airborne and Non-Airborne operations
- Performed HazMat duties and managed refueling operations
- Participated in special training missions as part of the elite 160th SOAR(A)
- Paratrooper and truck driver as part of training and refueling operations

Education

Nashville Software School (Feb 2021- Aug 2021)

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp (C#)

BBA Information Systems & Analytics Middle Tennessee State University (2018-2020)

- Business Application Development
- Advanced Web-Enabled Application Development
- Database Design Development
- Business Data Communications
- Info Systems Analysis & Design

- Object-Oriented Programing C#.NET
- Web Development
- (EXL) Dale Carnegie
 Communications and Human
 Relations Seminar

BA Art History Middle Tennessee State University (2002-2007)

- Fundamentals of Communication
- Research & Arg Writing

- Media Design & Visual Language
- Elem Logic & Critical Thinking